The next step is called a V step.
If you remember, I said a lot of the steps in step have their own lingo.
They also translate to what letters look like on the floor.
We have the basics step.
Now we're going to lengthen that step, make it more intense, by just taking our legs out a little bit wider to the edges of the bench.
It's still a 4 count move, but it's called a V step.
If you can see, I'm tracing a V on the floor.
From your perspective again.
We started with the basic step.
Now, we're just going to take it wider, so we have V step.
If I tap down and switch, that would be an alternating lead step of a V step.
It starts to again, increase my intensity because I'm starting to use the space around the bench or wider of the bench.
Then we'll start to move around the bench as well.
Heels all the way up.
You might hear it called an out, out, in, in with this sort of arm movement.
It is a front approach.
It is a basic step, but we lengthened the range of motion to increase the intensity.